what's up everybody phil bleckman with
barbin.com and today we are going to
talk about seven undeniable benefits of
kettlebell training if you want to learn
anything about kettlebell training just
head over to google type in bar ben
kettlebells and all of that coverage is
going to come up we have a lot of info
on kettlebells and kettlebell training
so let's get into it maybe your gym has
an entire rack of kettlebells just
waiting for you to get swinging or
you're working from home and you've got
a trusty kettlebell by your side in your
living room wherever you're training
with kettlebells you're bound to get
stronger become a better overall athlete
and fight off the sticking points in
your barbell lifts despite there being
no right way to hold a kettlebell these
implements offer unparalleled training
advantages unlike a barbell most
kettlebell exercises will generally
force you to contribute evenly with both
sides of your body and unlike a dumbbell
the nature of the load itself tends to
recruit more of your stabilizer muscles
from circuits to flows you can work with
kettlebells in more ways than you think
to develop power or improve your
cardiovascular endurance in case you're
not convinced here are seven big
benefits of working with kettlebells and
how to add them properly to your program
benefit number one low impact cardio
while traditional cardiovascular
exercises like jogging can be a huge
asset to strength athletes they can put
a lot of strain on the body adding hours
on the treadmill to your training might
not be the most effective cardio option
if your recovery isn't perfectly catered
to that plan since your feet remain
planted during even the most explosive
kettlebell moves you won't be placing
the same repetitive strain on your
joints and connective tissue as running
will many kettlebell exercises are
ballistic in nature making them ideal
for low impact cardiovascular training
benefit number two full body strength
part of the magic of kettlebells is that
they're not just good for your heart and
lungs they can also help skyrocket your
muscular strength and even build mass
throughout your body since most
kettlebell exercises recruit muscles
from head to toe everything from swings
to turkish get-ups will make you a much
stronger lifter kettlebell moves tend to
be either extremely slow and deliberate
like kettlebell windmills or fasten an
explosive like the cleaning press both
types activate muscles all over your
body which necessitates that your core
gets stronger and more stable your
entire body will get a serious boost of
strength from working with kettlebells
with a particular emphasis on the core
benefit number three coordination and
mobility to train effectively with
kettlebells you've got to be both
coordinated and mobile you can't perform
a proper kettlebell snatch without
sufficient full-body coordination
there's no way you'll be able to nail
such a complex move if you don't have
enough kinesthetic awareness to slip
your hand into the right position above
your head without slapping the bell on
your forearm you also need sufficient
shoulder mobility and overhead stability
to settle the weight in the top position
the good news is that you don't have to
start kettlebell training with good
coordination or mobility you can start
small you can build overhead mobility
coordination and stability with moves
like turkish getups and kettlebell
windmills you'll develop better hip
mobility and coordination through
training deep kettlebell goblet squats
and proper kettlebell deadlifts and
swings by the time you build up to the
more complex kettlebell moves your
coordination and mobility will have
grown tremendously benefit number four
training versatility you don't need to
drag yourself to the gym at four in the
morning to get a good workout the
versatility offered by kettlebell
training is a key benefit of these
implements you can literally work out
anywhere with kettlebells all within the
space taken up by a yoga mat there's
more to it than just train anywhere
advantages to kettlebells the
versatility offered by kettlebells means
that you can train with completely
different movement patterns that you
might be used to kettlebells help you
add challenges that are substantial even
at sub-maximal loads this means less
stress to your body overall while
stimulating growth in new areas of your
strength and athleticism benefit number
five fight imbalances with asymmetries
some kettlebell moves like swings and
dead bug pullovers require both hands on
the bell but most kettlebell exercises
are unilateral in nature this means that
you either perform reps with one side at
a time or have one bell in each hand so
your arms work independently this means
that strength and muscle asymmetries
don't stand much of a chance in the face
of kettlebell training plus if
aesthetics are your goal
balancing your strength can help you
equally stimulate each side of your body
benefit number six power development
grinding out a difficult lift takes a
tremendous amount of mental discipline
but moving weights quickly takes a
different kind of skill and mental
toughness kettlebells can help you
become a more powerful lifter from
swings and cleans to snatches and high
pulls many staple kettlebell lifts
require you to move the heavy weight
quickly you'll find that the more you
practice with kettlebells the more
efficient at force development you
become if you're a power lifter this can
help your main lifts by making your body
more comfortable under stress which
ultimately means you can lift heavier
regardless of speed if you're an olympic
lifter and power is the name of the game
kettlebells provide natural synergy the
sub maximal unilateral work will refine
your skills and make you more adept at
your barbell sport and finally benefit
number seven grip strength of course
well your whole body will get stronger
while working with kettlebells your grip
strength is worth mentioning in
particular kettlebell training often
involves timed circuits or flows during
which you don't drop the bell for
minutes at a time a huge contrast to the
bursts of barbell work kettlebells are
also phenomenal for building grip
strength because you're controlling the
bell while it's moving through different
planes during a snatch alone your
forearm will cycle through multiple
angles throughout the move so those are
some of the incredible benefits of
kettlebell training if you've never
trained with kettlebells before it's
never too late to get into it head over
to google type in kettlebells barban and
you'll actually see a list of the best
kettlebells recommended by barban.com
there are plenty of options available
from beginners to intermediate to
advanced kettlebell users so grab a
kettlebell next time you head into the
gym or at your home gym and get lifting
i'm phil blackman for barban.com thanks
for watching
[Music]
you